surfnetkids.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy » Surfnetkids

**Our Simple Privacy Pledge**

We take your privacy seriously, and we hate spam. For the fine print, continue on.

 **What is a Cookie?**

This site uses cookies to improve its functionality. Cookies are small text files stored on your computer or mobile device. They are made by your web-browser when you visit a website. Every time you go back to that website, your browser will send the cookie file back to the website’s server.

Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improving the user experience. They can also help to ensure that advertisements are more relevant to you and your interests. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. You can find more information about cookies at: [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

 **Our Cookie Usage**

Google, a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our sites. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visits to our sites and other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

 **Comments**

When visitors leave comments on this site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. Your comment may be scanned by a third-party service used to detect spam. An anonymized string created from your email address may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your name and profile picture are visible to the public in the context of your comment.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

 **Analytics**

We use Google Analytics to collect data about website usage. You can learn more about [How Google uses information](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). The easiest way to opt out of Google Analytics is use the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

 **What personal data we collect and why we collect it**

We collect names, email addresses, IP addresses from those that submit comments and contact forms so that we answer questions, improve community management, and automate the handling of spam and security threats.

 **Security Logs**

The IP address of visitors, user ID of logged in users, and username of login attempts are conditionally logged to check for malicious activity and to protect the site from specific kinds of attacks. Examples of conditions when logging occurs include login attempts, log out requests, requests for suspicious URLs, changes to site content, and password updates. This information is retained for 7 days.

 **How long we retain your data**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

 **What rights you have over your data**

You may send a request via the help desk at [Reply to Barbara](http://www.replytobarbara.com/) if you want your personal data deleted.

 **How do we protect your information?**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit, or access your personal information. These include SSL certificates, two-factor authorization, data encryption, and keeping our website software updated with all the newest security patches.

 **Embedded content from other websites**

This site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.) from other sites. Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

 **Who we share your personal data with**

We do not share your personally identifiable data with any third parties, except trusted partners that are committed to your privacy and are necessary to deliver our services to you:

  * our website host: [LiquidWeb](https://www.liquidweb.com/about-us/policies/privacy-policy/)
  * newsletter service: [Aweber](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm)
  * storage of our website backups: [ManageWP](https://managewp.com/privacy) and [Amazon S3](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/).
  * malware and security scans: [Sucuri’s SiteCheck](https://sucuri.net/privacy)
  * spam scan of comments: [Akismet](https://automattic.com/privacy-notice/)

 **Who We Are**

Have questions or comments? Best way to reach us is via the help desk at [Reply to Barbara](http://www.replytobarbara.com/).

Our website address is: https://www.surfnetkids.com

This site is owned by:

Surfnetkids.com, Inc.  
991C Lomas Santa Fe Dr. #415  
Solana Beach, CA 92075  
(858)793-8300  
Write to us at [ReplyToBarbara.com](https://www.replytobarbara.com/)

Last updated: June 14, 2018
